1200 Landing Ln. Moon Township, PA 15108 Campus Address

Alexander Cash

(c) 614-593-6899

aecst155@mail.rmu.edu|www.linkedin.com/in/alexander-cash| https://github.com/alcash55/Resume-Repository 5253 Stallion Ct. Liberty Township, OH 45011

Permanent Address

Graduation: May 2021

GPA: 3.10

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Current D1 student-athlete entering my senior year pursuing an integrated masters program at Robert Morris University. Working towards an ABET-accredited degree in Software Engineering. Focused on developing new business and engineering skills while excited and looking forward to utilizing my current knowledge and experience in the workforce.

EDUCATION

Robert Morris University, Moon Township, PA

- 4+1 Masters Program: Web & Mobile Information Systems
- · Major: Engineering, Concentration in Software Engineering
- Minor: Data Analytics
- · Dean's List Spring 2018

Key Classes

- C++ Programming
- Java Programming
- Advanced Java Programing
- Data Structures & Algorithms
- Fundamentals of Software Engineering
- Computer Architecture for Software Engineers
- Distributed Systems Implementation
- Database Management Systems
- Prototyping & Interfaces

Projects

- Student Course Registration
 - Created WBS, RMMM, SRS, Static Wireframe, Site Map, Usability Report, User Journey Map, and Personas to design project
 - Designed and developed using JavaFX and CSS
- Temperature Converter
 - o Created project using the Agile project method
 - Designed and developed using JavaFX and CSS
- Go Fish Distributed System
 - o Created project using the Agile project method
 - o Developed with C++ using multi-dimensional arrays

SKILLS

Dependability
Organization

Adaptability

Problem Solving

Communication

Programming Experience: Java, C++, Python, SQL, JsLinux

<u>Software Experience</u>: Visual Studio, Eclipse, GitHub, Autodesk AutoCAD, Autodesk Inventor, Autodesk Revit, SolidWorks, NI Multisim, Microsoft Visio, Microsoft Project, and Microsoft Office

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Low and Away lacrosse Assistant Coach

Greater Pittsburgh Area | June 2019 - Present

- · Joined as a practice coach working with all ages and promoted to join for summer tournaments for the top 2020 class
- Assist in running tryouts and evaluating players for the upcoming summer
- Communicate and teach defensive strategies

Resolute Lacrosse Head Defensive Coach

Columbus & Cincinnati, OH | May 2017-July 2018

- Joined as a junior coach assigned to work with the top 2022 graduating class and promoted to head defensive coach for the 2021 graduating class the following summer
- Assisted with designing practice plans, communicated weekend travel itineraries, and managed in-game player substitutions
- Worked an average of 8-10 hours a week and traveled across east coast states for tournaments

LEADERSHIP

Robert Morris University Men's D1 Lacrosse Team

Moon Township, PA | Aug. 2016-Present

- Dedicate 20+ hours a week practicing lacrosse, lifting, analyzing game and practice film, and community service, while balancing a full academic course load
- Developed teamwork, and leadership skills while participating in team building activities
- Achieved back to back conference championships (NEC) and making an NCAA appearance in the 2018 & 2019 seasons

Colonial Leadership Academy

Moon Township, PA | Oct. 2017-2018

• Studied and applied lessons from the book *Developing the Leader Within You* (John C. Maxwell) towards daily life on and off the field, while participating in interactive sessions designed to enhance leadership skills.

RMU Lead Program

Moon Township, PA | Aug. 2016

- Attended seminars about leadership with guest speakers
- · Preformed different teambuilding activities
- Participated in different service events within the local area